<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-27T23:21:44-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Andrew Schafer</title><subtitle>I'm a recent grad and transplant from Michigan finding ways to be useful and hopefully, entertaining.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">I’m Worried for my Generation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/culture/2018/07/19/Im_worried_for_our_generation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I'm Worried for my Generation" /><published>2018-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/culture/2018/07/19/Im_worried_for_our_generation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/culture/2018/07/19/Im_worried_for_our_generation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2018-07-19-worried_for_our_generation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo of Andrew holding a camera&quot; /&gt;
I’m worried for my generation, and not in the way you might think. Every ad, every speech, movie, and novel geared towards our generation creates a fantasy that we need to due what we love. And get paid for it.
Well, I don’t. Not exactly anyway. Don’t get me wrong, I followed a major that I was interested and have a decent job. Working on a project that isn’t bland, yet it isn’t writing, or photography, or art, or app design. I’m getting paid to do something because not everyone can and wants to do it.
That was a sucky realization. At first anyway. The truth is that not everyone can be a writer, AND be paid for it. My generation, and myself specifically, believe that if I’m not doing exactly what I love and am being paid then I’m failing myself.
Here’s my conclusion. I will have to work a job where I might not love everything that I do. But I can still do what I love to do, in whatever form that takes. And I won’t get paid for it at first, but I’m also not good. I need to get better, and never stop. That’s how I can do what I love, and maybe someday, only do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m worried for my generation, and not in the way you might think. Every ad, every speech, movie, and novel geared towards our generation creates a fantasy that we need to due what we love. And get paid for it. Well, I don’t. Not exactly anyway. Don’t get me wrong, I followed a major that I was interested and have a decent job. Working on a project that isn’t bland, yet it isn’t writing, or photography, or art, or app design. I’m getting paid to do something because not everyone can and wants to do it. That was a sucky realization. At first anyway. The truth is that not everyone can be a writer, AND be paid for it. My generation, and myself specifically, believe that if I’m not doing exactly what I love and am being paid then I’m failing myself. Here’s my conclusion. I will have to work a job where I might not love everything that I do. But I can still do what I love to do, in whatever form that takes. And I won’t get paid for it at first, but I’m also not good. I need to get better, and never stop. That’s how I can do what I love, and maybe someday, only do that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two Haves</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/culture/2017/08/07/two-haves.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Haves" /><published>2017-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/culture/2017/08/07/two-haves</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/culture/2017/08/07/two-haves.html">&lt;p&gt;I used to think there isn’t any possible way that my hobbies and career choice could be more different. If I’m not in front of a computer muscling through debugs, I’m most likely halfway up a mountain somewhere pretty far from home. Even the word “home” has a loose interpretation when I examine my own life. I’ve lived throughout the beautiful State of Michigan (a proud Spartan I might add), Louisville Kentucky, and most recently, Minneapolis Minnesota. Through many adventures, jobs, and dwellings, I’ve always searched for what I was truly passionate about. While the activities have taken many shapes, they all have same outcome, wonder. Wonder is the first time you saw a touch screen phone. Wonder is jumping out of an airplane and seeing the curvature of the Earth, watching Mr. Fredricksen float his house in the clouds, hiking the Adirondack Mountains and Wonder is the lens in which I view the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every project I’ve taken part of on this portfolio is in pursuit of evoking wonder or simply capturing it. To me, to be human is to wonder, to be curious and retrospective. It excites me how technology can make lives easier, more connected, and overall better with creative thinking and a few lines of code. Adventures down rivers, up mountains and through trails are great because of the people that I’ve shared that emotion and story with. In short, I’m a storyteller, photographer, designer, and developer chasing wonder.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I used to think there isn’t any possible way that my hobbies and career choice could be more different. If I’m not in front of a computer muscling through debugs, I’m most likely halfway up a mountain somewhere pretty far from home. Even the word “home” has a loose interpretation when I examine my own life. I’ve lived throughout the beautiful State of Michigan (a proud Spartan I might add), Louisville Kentucky, and most recently, Minneapolis Minnesota. Through many adventures, jobs, and dwellings, I’ve always searched for what I was truly passionate about. While the activities have taken many shapes, they all have same outcome, wonder. Wonder is the first time you saw a touch screen phone. Wonder is jumping out of an airplane and seeing the curvature of the Earth, watching Mr. Fredricksen float his house in the clouds, hiking the Adirondack Mountains and Wonder is the lens in which I view the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">20 Yr Old American Dream</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/culture/2016/07/04/20-yr-old-american-dream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="20 Yr Old American Dream" /><published>2016-07-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-07-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/culture/2016/07/04/20-yr-old-american-dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/culture/2016/07/04/20-yr-old-american-dream.html">&lt;p&gt;Today is America’s Independence day and there is no better day to talk about what’s been on my mind. Americans hold many values close to there hearts. (if you see “there” you’ll notice that grammar isn’t one of those things). Freedom, helping out hose in need (even if they don’t ask), equality, and star of today’s musings, the pursuit of the “American Dream”. As a kid, I saw this as a very simple goal: Have the ability to afford a cottage. (Cabin, lake house, whatever you prefer.) My favorite memories growing up are rooted in this dream that my parents were fortunate enough to realize. At the core of all these memories lies family, adventure, friends, an escape from day to day, and of course; food and water. By water, I’m not referring to the type that you drink, I’m talking about the kind you swim and boat in. As I’ve grown older and have had the luxury of more experience, my mentality has changed. To me, work is simply a means to an end. I find ways to thoroughly enjoy the time I get paid for, but works is not my reason for existing. To me, my goals is to experience as much as I possibly can with my life. I want to be able to explore; every weekend, every year. This means I need to be able to “check out” of work and just live. I see others that place money as the foundation of success because it allows them to have an escape in the form of a cottage or take lavish vacations. Then I see people like Hoot, my rafting guide this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2016-07-04-Pursuit_of_the_American_Dream.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the rafting trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He loves everyday. He doesn’t make a lot of money but he explores, has fun, and stays active every moment of his life. The American dream isn’t universal, just like success isn’t. To me, that’s the beauty of it, and honestly, it’s what it means to be an American: The opportunity to find a unique happiness.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today is America’s Independence day and there is no better day to talk about what’s been on my mind. Americans hold many values close to there hearts. (if you see “there” you’ll notice that grammar isn’t one of those things). Freedom, helping out hose in need (even if they don’t ask), equality, and star of today’s musings, the pursuit of the “American Dream”. As a kid, I saw this as a very simple goal: Have the ability to afford a cottage. (Cabin, lake house, whatever you prefer.) My favorite memories growing up are rooted in this dream that my parents were fortunate enough to realize. At the core of all these memories lies family, adventure, friends, an escape from day to day, and of course; food and water. By water, I’m not referring to the type that you drink, I’m talking about the kind you swim and boat in. As I’ve grown older and have had the luxury of more experience, my mentality has changed. To me, work is simply a means to an end. I find ways to thoroughly enjoy the time I get paid for, but works is not my reason for existing. To me, my goals is to experience as much as I possibly can with my life. I want to be able to explore; every weekend, every year. This means I need to be able to “check out” of work and just live. I see others that place money as the foundation of success because it allows them to have an escape in the form of a cottage or take lavish vacations. Then I see people like Hoot, my rafting guide this weekend.</summary></entry></feed>