<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-07T20:37:03-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Andrew Schafer</title><subtitle>I'm a recent grad and transplant from Michigan finding ways to be useful and hopefully, entertaining.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Frontier Ruined my Trip … Wait, Did They?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/06/08/frontier-ruined-my-trip.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frontier Ruined my Trip … Wait, Did They?" /><published>2019-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/06/08/frontier-ruined-my-trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/06/08/frontier-ruined-my-trip.html">&lt;p&gt;Frontier ruined my Trip … Wait, Did They?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common question you endure when you land after a spell of air travel is, “How was the flight”. 99% of the time, “It was fine” pretty much sums it up and it is always met with glowing approvals and anecdotes to past travel horror stories. The flight sticks in people’s mind longer than the sandwich they ordered for lunch in San Francisco or the cute Airbnb in the Poconos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I truly don’t understand the fascination and concern that’s applied to the logistics of air travel. Next time your in security look around and observe. Nobody can handle it. People lose their minds in worry and the simple truth is that just about everything is completely out of their control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, the flight is simply the vessel to get to the adventure. I try not to get hung up in worrying about lost bags, layovers, etc. Life is just easier when you just go with the flow and ride out delays, pack light with carry on only, and try to enjoy the commute with a movie or good book. You’ll get there right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theory was tested lasted weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flew to Denver. For one day. I was supposed to anyway. Below is a picture of my friends and I on Day 1 of 1. I don’t have a picture of us on Day 2 of 1 but if I did, we wouldn’t have been looking our best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/travel/2019/06-08-denver-day-trip_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Andrew and his friend in front of a wall mural at Denver Brewing Co.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to start at the beginning. This was the weekend for the inaugural event we proudly dubbed, “Microtravel”. The brilliant plan was to find bonkers cheap flights that left early in the morning and returned late that night. It would allow for no luggage and promised a light weight, adventurous day in a new city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All things considered, that’s exactly what it did. We arrived on time and instantly filled our day with a brewery tour of Coors and Blue Moon, some good food, and old fashioned exploring. We had great weather, good company, and I’m always a sucker for checking out new places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it went so well that when we got the notification that the flight was delayed for an hour, we cheered. “One more drink!” We had exclaimed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did get that drink, but the cheering slowly diminished as the departure kept getting pushed back. We witnessed an arrest in the terminal, boarded and deplaned, and waited some more. Frontier forgot to book a pilot. Totally understandable, who would have thought that would be an important part of our aeronautical journey. Frontier, silly silly airline. This lead to a cancellation with no flights until Monday, which even if that was an option, was selling for a cool $400 per seat. Oh, there also wasn’t enough seats for all of us. That lead to the only option left, renting a car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those without quick access to google maps, which is crazy because this is an online blog, Denver to Minneapolis is about 14 hours. With an ideal start time of 3:30 am following a day of brewery hopping that started at 4:00 am, I can’t think of a better road trip recipe. Oh, and the bulk of the drive was through Nebraska and Iowa. Picturesque.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, we packed light, and by light I mean absolutely nothing as the itinerary stopped at “hour 10 in Denver”. I have never been more exhausted, most likely stinky, and tired of farm fields in recent (let’s be honest, distant) memory. But we did it, we made it. That’s a bond that’s hard to break when you endure that type of experience. Am I gearing up for another road trip with those parameters. No. No. Not even a little. However, what a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the travel in “travel” really does leave a lasting impression, and is something worth being added to the story. In 10 years I might not remember the name of the beer I had a Blue Moon Brewery (Mango Wheat btw), but I will certainly remember the 14 hour road trip that was kicked off at the optimal time of 3:30 in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Frontier ruined my Trip … Wait, Did They?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Perfect Day Trip to Duluth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/06/05/day-trip-to-duluth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Perfect Day Trip to Duluth" /><published>2019-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/06/05/day-trip-to-duluth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/06/05/day-trip-to-duluth.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/travel/2019/06-05-duluth-day-trip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of Andrew and Jess standing on rocks in Lake Superior&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you really only need a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand, or remember if you know me, is that I’m from Michigan.  So recently in fact, I haven’t gotten a Minnesota license yet. One of my core beliefs, which especially applies when you are in a new place, is that people underestimate the possibilities of a day. It’s so common where people pass on weekend trips because they have one single thing already planned. This hurts me to my very core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I didn’t do that and instead, said yes to plans, to doing something, and went North.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I trust I don’t have to spend too much time on the drive; good tunes, chill vibes, and deep(ish) convos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-1-jay-cooke-state-park&quot;&gt;Stop 1: Jay Cooke State Park&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/travel/2019/06-06-cooke-map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Map of Jay Cooke State Park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the perfect way to break up to the drive. Beautifall falls and and bridges are right next to the parking lot and the rocks are open to climb around to explore the area. We took the Silver Creek Trail. When it followed the river it exposed many beautiful views, but in the interior wasn’t a must see and resulted in a tick encounter. Overall, the river kept the temperatures pleasant, the rocks formations were beautiful and allowed for some great exploration, and we skipped a few stones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the photo locations above? It resulted in these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/travel/2019/06-05-duluth-day-trip_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bridge of Rapids at Jay Cooke State Park&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/travel/2019/06-05-duluth-day-trip_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jess in the Falls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-2-duluth&quot;&gt;Stop 2: Duluth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hike was followed with a refreshing beer on the shores of Lake Superior in Duluth. Canal Park Brewery was amazing as always and we spent some time splashing around with a puppy named Oakley. See below for “awww”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/travel/2019/06-05-duluth-day-trip_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Golden Retriever splashing in Lake Superior&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-3-_ツ_&quot;&gt;Stop 3: ¯_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day was wrapped watching the sunset at a spot, it’s secret so no pics, somewhere along the North Shore. It was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekends, well days for that matter, really shouldn’t be underestimated. If you’re not careful, you can make them pretty fun.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I built my website with Jekyll (For Free)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/technology/2019/05/24/how-i-built-a-static-website-with-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I built my website with Jekyll (For Free)" /><published>2019-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/technology/2019/05/24/how-i-built-a-static-website-with-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/technology/2019/05/24/how-i-built-a-static-website-with-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/technology/2019/05-28-how-i-built-my-website.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wordpress versus Jekyll logos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part of writing this website, believe it or not, was to get started. There are so many options for hosting, content management, and languages. It absolutely can be overwhelming. In the journey of building this, I started with Jekyll two years ago. It went terribly. I got caught up in trying to find the best theme and spent to much effort fighting themes instead of understanding the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My career progressed into a role where I was working with a Sitecore implementation. In my undergrand, we didn’t touch on CMS (content management systems) and it felt unnecessary. Why not just build a backend and link to your own database? Why be stuck to certain rules and pay someone a lot of money for that pleasure? Eventually it became clear that it was all about scale. There isn’t a reason to have a developer code every page that is a little big custom. Having a separate authoring team does have extremely valuable cost savings. In my discovery period in getting familiar with the platform, I build out a proof of concept in Wordpress. Honestly it was fun. I saw how customizable it could be. The benefits of allowing guests to contribute, the thorough documentation,and it was a good skill to add to my quiver. However, it had one major downside: A cost to host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t see this website as a vehicle for earning substantial income and it didn’t seem to make sense to pay a monthly fee for a portfolio site when there were other options to host it for free. Looking on the site now, maybe there is opportunity for a wider audience to my content, by that certainly wasn’t the driving force for this project. What wordpress did really well was help me understand the concepts of a CMS, or in Jekyll’s case, a static site generator. Now that I understood the underlying development pattern, I went back to the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, the documentation on the site is incredibly well maintained and easy to follow. I recommend starting here with their &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/step-by-step/01-setup/&quot;&gt;step by step guide.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It guides you everywhere from setting up ruby and jekyll on your machine to building a base project. Another good resource I found was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T1itpPvFWHI&quot;&gt;Mike Dane&lt;/a&gt;. His tuturials really helped with my grasp of the basics and using Liquid. Liquid is the programming language you can use within your markup to pull in data from the site. From there I was able to write custom code that could pull select categories. This allowed me to solve the issue wanting more than one type of posts for images, videos, etc. Below is an example of how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place your category or categories in the front matter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot; data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;layout: post
categories: technology
title: How I built my website with Jekyll (For Free)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then created a collection layout that would pull in the correct category from the page (using front matter) and compare it with the post category from above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;{% if site.posts.size &amp;gt; 0 %}
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {% for post in site.posts%}
    {% if post.categories contains page.categories%}
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;post-item&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        {%- assign date_format = site.minima.date_format | default: &quot;%b %-d, %Y&quot; -%}
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;post-meta&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{{ post.date | date: date_format }}&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;post-link&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{ post.url | relative_url }}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
                {{ post.title | escape }}
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        {%- if site.show_excerpts -%}
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;{{ post.excerpt | strip_html | truncatewords:50 }}&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        {%- endif -%}
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {%endif%}
    {%endfor%}
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
{% endif %}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about this besides being able to fit my needs, is the integration with github pages. I can host the site absolutely free and can easily push up changes and add posts. If you have any questions, please reach out or check out the repository here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/schaferandrew/schaferandrew.github.io&quot;&gt;Andrew Schafer’s website repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="technology" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m Worried for my Generation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/culture/2018/07/19/Im_worried-for-our-generation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m Worried for my Generation" /><published>2018-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/culture/2018/07/19/Im_worried-for-our-generation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/culture/2018/07/19/Im_worried-for-our-generation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/culture/2018/07-19-worried_for_our_generation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo of Andrew holding a camera&quot; /&gt;
I’m worried for my generation, and not in the way you might think. Every ad, every speech, movie, and novel geared towards our generation creates a fantasy that we need to do what we love. And get paid for it.
Well, I don’t. Not exactly anyway. Don’t get me wrong, I followed a major that I was interested and have a decent job. Working on a project that isn’t bland, yet it isn’t writing, or photography, or art, or app design. I’m getting paid to do something because not everyone can and wants to do it.
That was a sucky realization. At first anyway. The truth is that not everyone can be a writer, AND be paid for it. My generation, and myself specifically, believe that if I’m not doing exactly what I love and am being paid then I’m failing myself.
Here’s my conclusion. I will have to work a job where I might not love everything that I do. But I can still do what I love to do, in whatever form that takes. And I won’t get paid for it at first, but I’m also not good. I need to get better, and never stop. That’s how I can do what I love, and maybe someday, only do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="culture" /><summary type="html">I’m worried for my generation, and not in the way you might think. Every ad, every speech, movie, and novel geared towards our generation creates a fantasy that we need to do what we love. And get paid for it. Well, I don’t. Not exactly anyway. Don’t get me wrong, I followed a major that I was interested and have a decent job. Working on a project that isn’t bland, yet it isn’t writing, or photography, or art, or app design. I’m getting paid to do something because not everyone can and wants to do it. That was a sucky realization. At first anyway. The truth is that not everyone can be a writer, AND be paid for it. My generation, and myself specifically, believe that if I’m not doing exactly what I love and am being paid then I’m failing myself. Here’s my conclusion. I will have to work a job where I might not love everything that I do. But I can still do what I love to do, in whatever form that takes. And I won’t get paid for it at first, but I’m also not good. I need to get better, and never stop. That’s how I can do what I love, and maybe someday, only do that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two Halves</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/culture/2017/08/07/two-halves.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Halves" /><published>2017-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/culture/2017/08/07/two-halves</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/culture/2017/08/07/two-halves.html">&lt;p&gt;I used to think there isn’t any possible way that my hobbies and career choice could be more different. If I’m not in front of a computer muscling through debugs, I’m most likely halfway up a mountain somewhere pretty far from home. Even the word “home” has a loose interpretation when I examine my own life. I’ve lived throughout the beautiful State of Michigan (a proud Spartan I might add), Louisville Kentucky, and most recently, Minneapolis Minnesota. Through many adventures, jobs, and dwellings, I’ve always searched for what I was truly passionate about. While the activities have taken many shapes, they all have same outcome, wonder. Wonder is the first time you saw a touch screen phone. Wonder is jumping out of an airplane and seeing the curvature of the Earth, watching Mr. Fredricksen float his house in the clouds, hiking the Adirondack Mountains and Wonder is the lens in which I view the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every project I’ve taken part of on this portfolio is in pursuit of evoking wonder or simply capturing it. To me, to be human is to wonder, to be curious and retrospective. It excites me how technology can make lives easier, more connected, and overall better with creative thinking and a few lines of code. Adventures down rivers, up mountains and through trails are great because of the people that I’ve shared that emotion and story with. In short, I’m a storyteller, photographer, designer, and developer chasing wonder.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="culture" /><summary type="html">I used to think there isn’t any possible way that my hobbies and career choice could be more different. If I’m not in front of a computer muscling through debugs, I’m most likely halfway up a mountain somewhere pretty far from home. Even the word “home” has a loose interpretation when I examine my own life. I’ve lived throughout the beautiful State of Michigan (a proud Spartan I might add), Louisville Kentucky, and most recently, Minneapolis Minnesota. Through many adventures, jobs, and dwellings, I’ve always searched for what I was truly passionate about. While the activities have taken many shapes, they all have same outcome, wonder. Wonder is the first time you saw a touch screen phone. Wonder is jumping out of an airplane and seeing the curvature of the Earth, watching Mr. Fredricksen float his house in the clouds, hiking the Adirondack Mountains and Wonder is the lens in which I view the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A 20 Year Old’s Perception of the American Dream</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/culture/2016/07/04/20-yr-old-american-dream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A 20 Year Old’s Perception of the American Dream" /><published>2016-07-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-07-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/culture/2016/07/04/20-yr-old-american-dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/culture/2016/07/04/20-yr-old-american-dream.html">&lt;p&gt;Today is America’s Independence day and there is no better day to talk about what’s been on my mind. Americans hold many values close to there hearts. (if you see “there” you’ll notice that grammar isn’t one of those things). Freedom, helping out hose in need (even if they don’t ask), equality, and star of today’s musings, the pursuit of the “American Dream”. As a kid, I saw this as a very simple goal: Have the ability to afford a cottage. (Cabin, lake house, whatever you prefer.) My favorite memories growing up are rooted in this dream that my parents were fortunate enough to realize. At the core of all these memories lies family, adventure, friends, an escape from day to day, and of course; food and water. By water, I’m not referring to the type that you drink, I’m talking about the kind you swim and boat in. As I’ve grown older and have had the luxury of more experience, my mentality has changed. To me, work is simply a means to an end. I find ways to thoroughly enjoy the time I get paid for, but works is not my reason for existing. To me, my goals is to experience as much as I possibly can with my life. I want to be able to explore; every weekend, every year. This means I need to be able to “check out” of work and just live. I see others that place money as the foundation of success because it allows them to have an escape in the form of a cottage or take lavish vacations. Then I see people like Hoot, my rafting guide this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/culture/2016/07-04-Pursuit_of_the_American_Dream.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the rafting trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He loves everyday. He doesn’t make a lot of money but he explores, has fun, and stays active every moment of his life. The American dream isn’t universal, just like success isn’t. To me, that’s the beauty of it, and honestly, it’s what it means to be an American: The opportunity to find a unique happiness.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="culture" /><summary type="html">Today is America’s Independence day and there is no better day to talk about what’s been on my mind. Americans hold many values close to there hearts. (if you see “there” you’ll notice that grammar isn’t one of those things). Freedom, helping out hose in need (even if they don’t ask), equality, and star of today’s musings, the pursuit of the “American Dream”. As a kid, I saw this as a very simple goal: Have the ability to afford a cottage. (Cabin, lake house, whatever you prefer.) My favorite memories growing up are rooted in this dream that my parents were fortunate enough to realize. At the core of all these memories lies family, adventure, friends, an escape from day to day, and of course; food and water. By water, I’m not referring to the type that you drink, I’m talking about the kind you swim and boat in. As I’ve grown older and have had the luxury of more experience, my mentality has changed. To me, work is simply a means to an end. I find ways to thoroughly enjoy the time I get paid for, but works is not my reason for existing. To me, my goals is to experience as much as I possibly can with my life. I want to be able to explore; every weekend, every year. This means I need to be able to “check out” of work and just live. I see others that place money as the foundation of success because it allows them to have an escape in the form of a cottage or take lavish vacations. Then I see people like Hoot, my rafting guide this weekend.</summary></entry></feed>